<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Tarik's Leadership Journey</title><link>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Tarik's Leadership Journey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Emotional Maturity</title><link>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/emotional-maturity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/emotional-maturity/</guid><description>The number one leadership trait is emotional maturity.
The easiest way to stay emotionally mature is through curiosity.
Because curiosity leads to a growth mindset.
The growth mindset sees every challenge as an opportunity to learn and grow rather than something to be mad about. (Yes, sometimes you need to be angry about things!)
The faster way to develop a growth mindset is to be willing to experiment rather than push back as the initial reaction by default.</description></item><item><title>Be Better to Increase Motivation</title><link>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/be-better-to-increase-motivation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/be-better-to-increase-motivation/</guid><description>When your motivation at work drops, before making any drastic changes, check the following fail-forward strategies. They have always worked for me!
Check if you lack domain expertise and spend time learning the product better. The lack of product knowledge often narrows your perspective on your work and its impact. When you know less, you participate less in meetings; you generate fewer ideas, which could lead to thoughts that involve worthlessness, imposter syndrome, and so on.</description></item><item><title>How to Get Quality Feedback</title><link>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/how-to-get-quality-feedback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/how-to-get-quality-feedback/</guid><description>If we want quality feedback, we must know to be vulnerable.
If we want to give quality feedback to our teams, we need to prepare a space for them to feel comfortable with being vulnerable.
Feedback is a two-way street. Without sharing our stories, whether failures or successes, we cannot get quality feedback that truly helps.
And we cannot give quality feedback if we don&amp;rsquo;t know enough about the person in front of us.</description></item><item><title>Leaders Must Listen</title><link>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/leaders-must-listen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/leaders-must-listen/</guid><description>Leaders must show patience to listen. While dominating every meeting doesn’t strengthen your authority, listening to others does not undermine it.
Meetings, especially the 1:1s, are not places to dictate your ideas breathlessly.
You must have meaningful dialogues with your peers and reports to find the truth and more innovative solutions.
Breathless leaders are quick to form their impressions about people and events, and they never spend time to confirm them.</description></item><item><title>Managers Need Emotional Maturity</title><link>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/managers-need-emotional-maturity/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.leadershipjourney.io/posts/managers-need-emotional-maturity/</guid><description>Emotional maturity is essential for a successful management career.
Vulnerability and emotional maturity are not mutually exclusive.
Emotional maturity is not to be a ghoul.
Emotional maturity is:
Not to be overly sensitive to events. To think before reacting. To stay calm and attentive. To see the world more objectively than through our elevated emotions. Not to confuse directness and honesty with being disrespectful. To be less self-centric and more outcome-oriented.</description></item></channel></rss>